Finding Aid for William G. Milliken papers 1961-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Miscellaneous 1960s-1982
  - Reports 1967-1982, 6.5 linear feet
    - Seafarer ELF Communications System
      - Draft Environmental Impact Statement for Site Selection, 4 folders (Box 1448)
    - Single Business Tax Advisory Task Force 1976 (Box 1448)
    - Small and Rural Communities
      - Small Cities and Rural Areas Growth Conference 1980 (Box 1448)
      - Task Force Final Report 1981 (Box 1448)
      - Michigan Small Cities Program (Commerce) 1982 (Box 1448)
    - Social Services
      - Annual Plan of Department for Fiscal Year 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 1448)
      - Program Statistics, Fiscal 1972 (Box 1448)
      - Proposed Annual Plans 1978, 1979 (Box 1448)
    - State Model Cities Coordination (Bureau of Program and Budget) 1972 (Box 1448)
    - State Officers Compensation 1982 (Box 1448)
    - Substance Abuse Among Michigan's Senior Citizens: Issues and the Future 1978 (Box 1448)
    - Taxes
      - Property Tax Revision Task Force 1976, 3 folders (Box 1448)
      - Study of Michigan Tax Structure (DMB) 1978 (Box 1448)
      - Taxes on Industry and Individuals: Michigan Compared to Competitor States (Citizens Research Council of Michigan) 1969 (Box 1448)
    - Telecommunications Master Plan (TELEMAP) for Michigan (DMB) (Box 1449)
    - Transportation
      - Interim Findings of Interagency Transportation Coordinating Council 1976 (Box 1449)
      - Lake-Link Transportation Corporation 1979 (Box 1449)
      - Public Transportation Services in Southeast Michigan 1975 (Box 1449)
      - Michigan Transportation Study 1976 (Box 1449)
    - Unemployment Insurance (Departments of Labor, Commerce, and MESC) (Box 1449)
    - Wastewater Treatment, Regional 1969 (Box 1449)
    - Weatherization Assistance for Low-Income Persons (Department of Energy) 1978 (Box 1449)
    - Women in Michigan State Government 1978 (Box 1449)
    - Workmen's Compensation Reform
      - Comparison of Labor, Industry, and Reform Positions on Major Issues (Box 1449)
      - Governor's Advisory Committee 1975 (Box 1449)
      - Comparative Cost Analysis of SB 1178/HB----, SB 355/HB 4399 and SB 1099/HB, 5556 (Box 1449)
    - Youth Service Information System Plan 1973 (Box 1449)
  - Special Reports of the Governor 1970-1982, 0.5 linear feet
    - Budget Messages 1980-1983, 4 folders (Box 1449)
    - Economic Reports 1970-1981, 5 folders (Box 1449)
    - Employment Plan 1981-1982 (Box 1449)
    - Meet the Press 1977 (Box 1449)
    - Five-Year Full Employment Plan 1981 (Box 1449)
    - Program Policy Guidelines 1974-1976, 2 folders (Box 1449)
  - Departments and Commissions Annual Reports, 0.4 linear feet
    - Administration. 1971-1972 (Box 1449)
    - Civil Rights Commission 1972-1973 (Box 1449)
    - Education 1967-1968 (Box 1449)
    - Employment Security Commission 1970-1973, 3 folders (Box 1449)
    - Ethics Board 1979-1980 (Box 1449)
    - Management and Budget 1972-1973 (Box 1449)
    - Physical Fitness and Health (Michigan) 1977 (Box 1449)
    - Racing Commissioner 1973 (Box 1449)
    - Social Services
      - Central Registry 1977 (Box 1449)
      - Inspector General 1977 (Box 1449)
      - Internal Audits 1977 (Box 1449)
      - Quality Control and Statistics 1978 (Box 1449)
    - Substance Abuse Services 1978-1979 (Box 1449)
    - Treasury 1972 (Box 1449)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1969-1971, 5 volumes (Box 1452)
- Audio-Visual Material
  The Audio-Visual Material subgroup consists of artifacts, photographs, scrapbooks, and sound recordings They are artificial groupings of similar materials gathered together in the course of processing.
  - Artifacts
    - Artifacts- (Box 1450)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs (Box 1451)
  - Sound Recordings
    Transferred to State Archives
    - Press Conferences
      - Undated-WLUC (10/22) (Box 1772)
      - 1969
        - January and February, 2 tapes (Box 1772)
        - May 27 (Box 1772)
        - June 6, 12, 27/Wood Program, 2 tapes (Box 1772)
        - July 15-September 10 (Box 1772)
        - September 10-October 30; November 5-December 19 (Box 1772)
        - October 23 (Box 1772)
        - Date Uncertain (perhaps summer) (Box 1772)
      - 1970-1972
        - January 7-February 24 (Box 1772)
      - March 5, 1970-May 28, 1970, 2 tapes
        - April 29, 1970 (Box 1772)
        - June 2-August 25, 1970 (Box 1772)
        - September 21, 1970-January 26, 1971 (Box 1772)
        - October 27, 1971-March 9, 1972, 3-3/4 ips (Box 1772)
        - March 9; April 26-June 8, 1972 (Box 1772)
        - March 11, 16, 26 1972 (Box 1772)
    - Other Broadcasts
      - Undated
        - Evening with the Governor, 7-1/2 ips (Box 1772)
        - People (Box 1772)
      - 1968
        - Across the Gap. March 19 (Box 1772)
        - Interview with Lt. Governor Milliken for CPC Lee Murray (Box 1772)
        - Show. November 6 (Box 1772)
      - 1969
        - Tax Question Interview at Michigan State University (Box 1772)
        - January 10 (Box 1772)
        - Sunday Supplement, January 26 (Box 1772)
        - Governor on Community Colleges. November 13 (Box 1772)
      - 1970
        - Governor's Report (Wood), April 9, 7-1/2 ips (Box 1772)
      - 1971
        - WWJ "SPEAK-OUT," June 9, 7-1/2 ips (Box 1772)
      - 1973
        - Milliken/Ferency-"Fiscal Reform," April 6 (Box 1772)
        - Message to the Legislature. September 16 (Box 1772)
      - 1974
        - State of the State (Box 1772)
    - Inaugural Speech January 1, 1971, 2 tapes (Box 1772)
    - Swearing In. January, 1969 (Box 1772)
    - Issues
      - PBB
        - The PBB Dilemma, Bob Lee. Fetzer Broadcasting (Box 1773)
        - Channel 9, Cadillac. Aired September, 1977, videocassette (Box 1773)
        - McNeil-Lehrer Report. December, 1976 (Box 1773)
        - Bill Bond's Detroit. October 22, 1979, October 29, 1979, audiocassettes (Box 1773)
      - Single Business Tax Advisory Task Force Hearings
        - Flint November 16, 1976, 3-3/4 ips (Box 1773)
        - Gaylord December 14, 1976, 2 tapes 3.75 ips (Box 1773)
        - Grand Rapids December 8, 1976, 2 tapes 3.75 ips (Box 1773)
        - Lansing December 21, 1976, 2 tapes 3.75 ips (Box 1773)
        - Mt. Pleasant December 3, 1976, 3-3/4 ips (Box 1773)
        - Northern Michigan University November 18, 1976, 3-3/4 ips (Box 1773)
        - Pontiac (n.d.) (Box 1773)
    - Reagan-Carter Presidential Debate 1980 (Box 1773)
    - Topical
      - Detroit Press Club 1969 Stag Steakout (Box 1773)
      - Farm Bureau Tape. May 20 (Box 1773)
      - Governor's Conferences
        - Bay De Noc College 1982 (Box 1773)
        - Houston, Texas. KUHT-TV 1972 (Box 1773)
        - Mackinac Island. August 16-17, 1971 (Box 1773)
      - Journal 173-"Judgment on the Courts," April 4, 1973 (Box 1773)
      - Kelly Press Conference June 20, 1972, 3-3/4 ips (Box 1773)
      - Man on the Moon circa 1970, 7-1/2 ips (Box 1773)
      - Michigan Agriculture, May 20, 7-1/2 ips (Box 1773)
      - Michigan Classroom TV. WMSB-TV February, 1969 (Box 1773)
Index to staff responsibility by subject area
The following list may assist in providing some subject access to the Staff Files. It lists broad policy and program areas and the staff members principally responsible for them.
Aging
Janis Bocksay
Stan Pratt
Agriculture
Phil Kazmierski
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Dennis Payne
Affirmative Action
Gordon Alexander
Alcohol and Drug Abuse
Steven Fetter
Richard McLellan
Arts
Holly Angell
Elizabeth Schleiffarth
Kathy Stariha
Budget
Gordon Alexander
Glenn Allen
Bob Law
Stan Pratt
Chrysler Corporation
Glenn Friedly
Civil Rights
Dave Duncan
Commerce
Pat Babcock
Community Development
Office of Lt. Governor
Linda Slotsema
Consumer Affairs
Christine Fedewa
Corrections
Barbara Debrodt
Steven Fetter
Departments and Commissions
Billie Harrison Phil Kazmierski Bob Law Bill Long
Economic Growth and Development
Pat Babcock Dave Duncan Jeff Graham Linda Slotsema George Weeks
Education
Dave Duncan
Don Gordon
Phil Kazmierski
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Emergency Disasters
Dennis Payne
Energy
Pat Babcock Linda Slotsema George Weeks
Environment
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
William Lukens
Marc Obershulte
Dennis Payne
Bill Rustem
Executive Council
Billie Harrison
Federal Issues
Glenn Friedly
Linda Slotsema
Governors' Associations and Conferences
Tom DeCair
Glenn Friedly
Linda Slotsema
Handicapped Concerns
Glenn Friedly
Hazardous Wastes
Dennis Payne
Bill Rustem
Health
Dave Duncan Craig Ruff
High Technology
Bob Law
Housing
Pat Babcock George Weeks
Human Services
Janis Bocskay
Stan Pratt
Craig Ruff
Linda Slotsema
Intergovernmental Relations
Glen Friedly
Labor
Pat Babcock
Dave Duncan
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
George Weeks
Legal Matters
Barbara Debrodt
Peter Ellsworth/Ken Frankland
Steven Fetter
Legislative Matters
Glen Allen
Pat Babcock
Richard Helmbrecht P
Phil Kazmierski
Bob Law
Bill Long
George Weeks
Mental Health
Pat Babcock
Janis Bocskay
Dave Duncan
William Lukens
Stan Pratt
Military Affairs
Richard McLellan
PBB
Pat Babcock
Kathy Stariha
George Weeks
Personnel
Gordon Alexander
Don Gordon
Pesticides
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Press
Jeff Graham
George Weeks
Public Health
Pat Babcock
Janis Bocskay
Dave Duncan
Stan Pratt
Craig Ruff
Racing
Phil Kazmierski
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Recipient Rights
Manfred Tatzmann
Recreation Bond
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Social Services
Pat Babcock
Janis Bocskay
Craig Ruff
State of the State
Jeff Graham
Taxes
Pat Babcock
Don Gordon
Jeff Graham
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Stan Pratt
George Weeks
Transportation
Phil Kazmierski
James Kellogg/Mark Mason
Urban Affairs
Jeff Graham
Linda Slotsema
Youth/Juveniles
Pat Babcock
Barbara Debrodt.
Richard McLellan